I think the time has come for me to
我想是时候让我
address the lightroom-shaped elephant in
向Lightroom形状的大象发表讲话
the room
房间
after a recent review of dark table by a
在最近一篇关于暗桌的评论之后
very popular photography website I've
非常受欢迎的摄影网站我已经
decided I'll give my two cents about the
我决定给出我的两点看法
whole Lightroom versus dark room
整间灯光房与暗室
comparison I've been using Lightroom
比较我一直使用的Lightroom
since its Inception and have been a
从它诞生以来一直是一个
Lightroom user until late 2020s
Lightroom用户持续到2020年代末
with all the different versions of
使用所有不同版本的
Lightroom I will focus on Lightroom
Lightroom我将专注于Lightroom
classic for desktop
经典台式机
I'd like to begin with a conclusion dark
我想以一个黑暗的结论开始
table is an application that gives you
表是一个应用程序 它为您提供
more control of your image formation and
更好地控制您的图像形成和
image formation pipeline dark table is
成像流水线暗表是
better if you like spending time
如果你喜欢花时间就更好了
crafting each image and require finer
精心制作每幅图像 并要求更精细
control
控制
dark table also includes better capture
暗桌还包括更好的捕获
repair tools especially for highlight
特别针对高光的修复工具
recovery
回收
Lightroom on the other hand provides
另一方面 Lightroom提供
quick consistent results that are
快速、一致的结果是
satisfactory the entry barrier is very
令人满意的是 进入门槛很高
low as it requires virtually no
低 因为它几乎不需要
knowledge on technical details of color
关于色彩技术细节的知识
image formation and image pipeline all
成像和成像流水线
the technical work is done by Adobe
技术工作由Adobe完成
Engineers behind the scenes since I'm a
幕后工程师 因为我是一个
big fan of bad analogies here's one
这里是一个糟糕类比的铁杆粉丝
doctable is a rally car it will produce
Doctable是一款它将生产的拉力汽车
results that are unparalleled given the
结果是无与伦比的 因为
right driver the driver needs to be
正确的司机司机必须是
experienced knowledgeable and patient if
如果经验丰富 知识渊博 有耐心
everything goes well the driver will
一切顺利 司机会的
enjoy the drive and will be satisfied
享受这段旅程 你会满意的
with the result
结果就是
however the rally car is awful if all
然而 拉力赛车真的很糟糕
you need to do is drive to work pick up
你需要做的就是开车去上班
your kids from school and get some
你的孩子们从学校拿到一些
groceries
食品杂货
and this is where a Lightroom comes in
这就是Lightroom的用武之地
Lightroom is a minivan practical easy to
Lightroom是一款实用易用的小型货车
drive
驾驶
it can get 7 people from point A to
它可以让7个人从A点到
point B with ease and comfort you don't
B点轻松舒适 你不需要
need special knowledge of the limits of
需要具备以下方面的专门知识
your engine nor do you need an ear
你的引擎也不需要耳朵
protection or a helmet it looks nice it
防护罩或头盔 看起来不错
drives smooth and it gets the job done
驾驶顺畅 就能完成工作
day in Day Out so which is better a
日复一日 所以哪一个更好
rally car or a minivan
拉力车或小型货车
is a rally car a good replacement for a
拉力赛车是不是很好的替代品？
minivan which one gives you more driving
哪辆小型货车能让你开得更快？
pleasure and this exactly is the point
快乐 而这正是关键所在
it even is highlighted in dark table's
它甚至在黑暗的桌子上突出显示
GitHub dark table is not a free Adobe
GitHub暗桌不是免费的Adobe
Lightroom replacement it is a digital
替换Lightroom 这是一款数码产品
image developing software and it can
图像开发软件 它可以
produce a result that is identical to
产生与相同的结果
what Lightroom can produce
Lightroom能产生什么
also includes a form of digital image
还包括一种形式的数字图像
management but that is about where the
管理 但这是关于哪里的
similarities with Lightroom end I see
我看到了与Lightroom End的相似之处
dark table more of a laboratory where
黑暗的桌子更像是一个实验室
you're free to experiment and really
你可以自由地进行实验 真的
develop your photos
冲洗你的照片
I see Lightroom as a more of a photo
我认为Lightroom更像是一张照片
retouching software where you start with
润色软件从哪里开始
a good Baseline provided by Adobe
Adobe提供的良好基准
engineers and then you make adjustments
工程师 然后你进行调整
according to your taste or preference
根据您的口味或喜好
if I was forced to point out the most
如果我不得不指出最重要的
impactful difference between the two
两者之间的巨大差异
software I'd probably say it's dark
软件我可能会说它是黑暗的
tables filmic RGB I suppose many people
餐桌电影RGB我想很多人
would like me to say that dark table is
想让我说那张暗桌是
scene referred and litum is display
参考场景并显示字母
referred but I'm not going to say that
但我不会这么说
filmic RGB and its highlight
电影RGB及其亮点
reconstruction tool are incredibly
重建工具令人难以置信
strong and provide incredible control
强大并提供令人难以置信的控制
that being said Lightroom does something
话虽如此 Lightroom做了一些事情
similar to filming however it's all
与拍摄类似 但这一切都是
buried somewhere deep and it's not at
埋在很深的地方 它不在
all exposed to the user
所有内容都向用户公开
I'm pretty sure it's hitting under
我很确定它正在下沉
profiles but it could be somewhere under
个人资料 但可能在下面的某个地方
calibration the second is powerful tool
校准第二个是强有力的工具
as the first one is their ability to
因为第一个是他们的能力
reorder the modules the ability to turn
对模块进行重新排序 以便能够
them off and on the ability to duplicate
他们断断续续地拥有复制的能力
and masked each one of them
把他们每个人都蒙住了
this gives incredible control of image
这让人难以置信地控制了图像
processing pipeline control the
处理管道控制
Lightroom simply does not give you
Lightroom根本不会给你
lastly without going too much in depth I
最后 我不说得太深入 我
have to mention that dark table is open
不得不提一下 那张暗桌是开着的
source software that is free of adobe's
免费的源软件adobe
whims and ever-changing licenses
异想天开和不断变化的执照
Remember You Don't Own Lightroom you
记住 你不是Lightroom的主人
just lease it it's Adobe software that's
把它租出去吧 这是Adobe软件
on loan to you all those collections you
借给你所有的收藏品
made are proprietary to Adobe software
是Adobe软件的专有产品
you're fully locked in if you break the
如果你打破了 你就完全被锁住了
Euler and Adobe terminates your license
Euler和Adobe将终止您的许可证
all you end up having is a brick catalog
你最终得到的只是一本实体目录
file that can only be opened with
只能使用打开的文件
Lightroom
Lightroom
sure you can export xmps but those XMP
当然 您可以导出XMP 但那些XMP
is loaded or converted will not yield
被加载或转换不会产生
the exact same results on a different
完全相同的结果在不同的
software
软件
Lightroom is incredibly fast every
Lightroom的速度令人难以置信地
change you make is instantaneous
你所做的改变是瞬间的
importing comparing exporting is
导入比较导出为
lightning fast something that dark table
像闪电一样快的东西 那张黑桌子
sucks so much at
在这方面太烂了
there we go every tweak requires
我们去那里 每一次调整都需要
recomputation
重新计算
whereas Lightroom processes everything
而Lightroom处理一切
much faster
快得多
Lightroom also has a benefit of being an
Lightroom还有一个好处 那就是成为
adobe software
Adobe软件
which includes support Cloud features
其中包括支持云功能
and interoperability
和互操作性
there's like what mobile Lightroom for
就像移动Lightroom的用途一样
iPad than others you can take your
IPad比其他你可以带着你的
presets on the go and use them to
移动中的预设 并使用它们来
develop your roll captures you shot on
开发您的滚动捕捉您的拍摄
your phone and lastly Lightroom is
你的手机 最后是Lightroom
incredibly intuitive all the complexity
令人难以置信的直觉所有的复杂性
is hidden and automated for you so you
为您隐藏并自动执行 因此您
don't need to become a color scientist
不需要成为一名色彩科学家
to be able to develop a photo I think
我认为能够冲洗一张照片
that is an incredible selling point
这是一个难以置信的卖点
especially for hobbyists
尤其是对业余爱好者来说
now I'm going to get attacked by fans of
现在我要被粉丝攻击了
both software just because I didn't
两个软件都是因为我没有
mention this obscure use case or that
提到这个或那个晦涩难懂的用例
obscure feature the fact is you can get
晦涩难懂的特征事实是你可以
excellent results with both applications
这两个应用程序都取得了出色的效果
one group of users will prefer Lightroom
一组用户将更喜欢Lightroom
due to its sheer quality of life and
由于它纯粹的生活质量和
speed other group of users will prefer
更快的速度是其他用户群喜欢的
dark table due to its Advanced refined
深色餐桌因其高级精致
control of the image forming process and
图像形成过程的控制和
pixel pipeline
像素流水线
and now it's time to say something
现在是时候说点什么了
rather controversial I think dark table
很有争议性 我觉得暗桌
is a better piece of software for both
是一款对两者都更好的软件
professionals and hobbyists
专业人士和业余爱好者
professionals will find it incredibly
专业人士会难以置信地发现
liberating having the amount of control
解放有控制力的量
of every step of their development
他们发展的每一步
pipeline thanks to the work of color
多亏了色彩的工作 流水线
conscious developers dark tables tools
有意识的开发人员暗表工具
are incredibly aware of what they do to
令人难以置信地知道他们做了什么
color preventing Hue shifts drifts
防止色调漂移的颜色
clipping and other mathematical nonsense
剪裁和其他数学上的废话
everything can break if you push it too
如果你太用力 一切都会破碎
far however going back to my silly rally
然而 回到我愚蠢的集会上
car analogy dark table is much easier to
汽车类黑桌就容易多了
drive into a wall hobbyists such as
开车撞墙的爱好者 比如
myself might find dark table
我自己可能会找到黑暗的桌子
inspirational I know I did it reignited
鼓舞人心的我知道我做到了重新点燃
my curiosity and I wanted to learn more
我的好奇心和我想要了解更多
I wanted to build and develop my photos
我想要建立和冲洗我的照片
not just tweak them I wanted to feel
不只是调整它们 我想感受
that I'm creating each and every
我创造了每一个
Captured Moment
捕捉到的瞬间
table filled this desire at 110 percent
餐桌以110%的比例满足了这一愿望
it's an excellent tool for education and
它是一种极好的教育工具
tinkering and will very likely reignite
修修补补 很可能会重新点燃
a smoldering love for photography lastly
最后 对摄影的浓浓热爱
dark table is yours the developers
黑暗的桌子是你的 开发商
kindly provide the software with a gpl3
请为该软件提供一个gpl3
license
许可证
which means you can download it
这意味着你可以下载它
and once you do it's yours no update is
一旦你这样做了 它就是你的了 没有更新
no license service no compatibility
无许可服务无兼容性
issues the fact that dark table is open
说明暗桌是开着的
source is difficult to believe as the
消息来源很难相信 因为
software is incredibly stable and
软件非常稳定 而且
Incredibly powerful it is absolutely
令人难以置信的强大 它绝对是
ready for professional use and it gets
准备好用于专业用途 它就会
better by the month I really do think
我真的觉得一个月比一个月好
it's an underrated piece of software and
这是一款被低估的软件
I really think that every person who has
我真的认为每一个有过
true nerdy passion for photography
真正的书呆子对摄影的热情
should give it a try and not just run
应该试一试 而不仅仅是跑步
the software and move a couple of
软件 并移动了几个
Sliders but give it a real go use it for
滑块 但给它一个真正的Go使用它
a week watch some tutorials read some
一周看一些教程读一些
documentation promise you're going to
文件承诺你将会
have a difficult time going back to
有一段时间很难回到
Lightroom
Lightroom
or not
或者不是
so that's the rundown of the two very
这就是这两个非常简单的
different software packages I've avoided
我避免过的不同的软件包
comparing them side to side as there's
将它们进行左右比较 因为
no point in doing so as I mentioned
如我所说 这样做没有意义
before both can perform very well and it
在两者都能表现得很好之前 它
would be impossible to say which photo
不可能说出是哪张照片
was made with Lightroom and which one
是用Lightroom制作的 哪一个
was made with dark table comparing them
是用深色桌子做的 比较它们
side by side is absolutely useless oh
肩并肩绝对没用哦
yeah and if you made it this far don't
是的 如果你走到了这一步
forget to subscribe maybe show this
忘记订阅也许显示这个
video to your nerdy friend that might be
视频给你的书呆子朋友
interested in pushing their photography
有兴趣推动他们的摄影
skills to the next level I'll see you
技能提升到下一个层次再见
soon bye
再见
[Music]
[音乐]